# **Sherilyn A. Moline**

Tampa, Florida • Phone (813) 786-0525

E-mail: <a href="mailto:smoline@gmail.com">smoline@gmail.com</a> Portfolio: <a href="http://SherilynMoline.me">http://SherilynMoline.me</a>

#### **WEB APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER**

Team oriented, quality minded, and motivated Ruby on Rails Developer with a solid record of accomplishments emphasizing training and development management in a highly competitive, rapidly growing industry. Demonstrated leadership, problem solving, and planning skills resulting in an integrated system of creative, timely, and practical programs.

Additional strengths:

Ruby on RailsHTMLProblem SolvingErbCSSCommunicatingMVCSassTeam BuildingAgile DevelopmentJavaScriptResearchingSQLjQueryTroubleshooting

Postgresql Test Driven Development Training

#### PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Worked in a Team of Ruby on Rails Developers. Using github the team created a silent auction web application using Rails 5.0, Ruby 2.4, bcrypt, OmniAuth, and Shrine. Using Agile Development we delivered a mvp with time to spare. Result: Delivered a customizable web application that could be used at any number of Fundraising Galas. The client was pleased.

**Built MacDonald's computer support team.** Company received new computer support contract for all MacDonald's using IBM machines. Built team, wrote procedures, and trained all the technical support members from scratch. **Result:** From day one, computer support was flawless. MacDonald's loved it.

Team Member of the first PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) virtual private network support team. The company landed the contract without any experience whatsoever. Researched, trained and coordinated this monumental task from its inception. Result: Our support allowed the first high-speed internet access to company servers on an international scale.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Ruby on Rails Program Graduate, The Iron Yard

March 2017 - June 2017

 Attended 12-week intensive back-end engineering course designed to give the students the tools and experience needed to enter a career as a junior web applications developer

#### President, Moline Services, Inc.

#### January 2011 - Present

- Business support company providing professional services on a contract basis to small businesses and sole practitioner law firms.
- Including administrative support, office management, professional photography, and computer and network support.

# Office Manager, West Coast Family Practice

# April 2007 - August 2009

Provided administrative support to the owner of the practice, including creating
procedures for new web based insurance pre-authorizations, and eligibility checks.
Researched the new market of EMR software for our practice upgrade. Familiar with
CollaborateMD and Practice Fusion software solutions.

#### President, ProTechConnect, Inc.

#### April 2005 - April 2007

 Computer support company providing business and home technical computer support.

# Training Coordinator, IBM End User Support

#### April 1998 - April 2004

# **Promoted to Training Manager in August 2001**

- Worked in an expanded role that included bringing in new clients, project management, quality assurance, and root cause analysis.
- Continued to write training programs and classes, and coordinate training.
- Worked as the Knowledge Manager on a multi-level database management project with IBM, developing processes and writing policy.

# Promoted to Team Lead in April 2000

• Responsible for overall productivity and morale of employees, monitor phone system, complete administrative reports, auditing documentation, research customer satisfaction issues, and training of new employees.

## **Promoted to Training Coordinator in March 1999**

- Worked with Supervisors to schedule training classes for rollouts of new software, and training of new employees.
- Responsible for training reports, the Training Bulletin Board, maintaining training room, software and equipment.

#### **Computer Support Specialist in April 1998**

- Telephone support for over 200 companies and 150 different products, troubleshooting, configuration and basic "how to" assistance.
- Develop curriculum for new software rollouts, as well as existing software.

## **EDUCATION / TRAINING / CERTIFICATIONS**

Bachelor of Science Degree in Management Information Systems
University of South Florida
Table 1

Tampa, FL - 2008

Ruby on Rails Program Graduate, The Iron Yard

St.Petersburg, FL - 2017